Ali Akbar Sazish

Full-stack developer with over **4 years of experience**, specializing in frontend development using **JavaScript**, **TypeScript**, **and React** to create innovative and user-friendly interfaces. Excellent communication and collaboration skills, and a passion for learning and adapting to new technologies.

Iran, Tehran

sazishaliakbar@gmail.com

+989100473242

LinkedIn | GitHub | Portfolio

WORK EXPERIENCE

Frontend Developer

Apr 2022 - Present

Artam Almas Alborz

- Develop and maintain 3 responsive web applications to enhance the user experience for over 1K+ customers.
- Collaborate with back-end developers to integrate front-end and back-end functionalities.
- Translate design concepts into functional code by working with UI/UX designers.
- Implementing responsive design and ensuring cross-browser compatibility.

Tech Skills: JavaScript, TypeScript, React, jQuery, Bootstrap, Laravel, SQL, MSSQL.

Web Developer

Feb 2020 - May 2021

ADRAS

- Developed, with a team of 10 developers, a centralized system for managing employee records and official correspondence in governmental civil organizations.
- Independently developed two modules and collaborated on three projects, enabling
 efficient management of letters, employee attendance, records, tasks, and salary
 payments.
- Played an essential role in deploying the software to over 3,000 active users as part of a 189-member IT and web development team.

Tech Skills: JavaScript, jQuery, Tailwind CSS, Laravel, SQL, MySQL.

Database Manager

Sep 2018 - Jan 2020

Ministry of Industry and Commerce

- Collaborated in designing and developing databases for large data volumes.
- Managed and maintained Databases to ensure that the databases are running smoothly.
- Implemented data security policies and controls to significantly increase safeguarding against unauthorized access and potential breaches.
- Ensured timely backup and recovery processes to minimize data loss and downtime.

Tech Skills: SQL, MSSQL, PHP, JavaScript and Bootstrap.

Biometric Technical Member

Feb 2017 - Aug 2018

Ministry of Higher Education

- Registered Kankor Examination volunteers meticulously to ensure their identity by capturing their information, taking their photo, and collecting their fingerprints.
- Designed and issued identification cards for the volunteers from scratch.
- Consolidated data from multiple sources and integrated it into a centralized database, resulting in significant cost savings for the government.

Tech Skills: MySQL, Kankory, Photoshop, Backup and Recovery.

VOLUNTEERING

Mentor (Volunteer) | Part Time | Remote

May 2023 - Aug 2023

Microverse

- Mentored junior web developers and provided technical support through code reviews.
- Proposed improvements to code organization to improve code quality and performance.
- Provided advice and tips on how to maintain motivation to maintain longevity in the program.

SKILLS

Front-End: JavaScript, TypeScript, React, Redux Toolkit, jQuery, Jest, Bootstrap, Tailwind CSS, HTML5, CSS3, SASS.

Back-End: PHP, Laravel, SQL, Node.js

Tools & Methods: API, PWA, Webpack, Git, GitHub, TDD, Photoshop, Davinci Resolve.

Soft Skills: Teamwork, Communication, Problem Solving, Time Management.

EDUCATION

Kabul University, Bachelor in Computer Science, Afghanistan, Kabul. Feb 2012 - Nov 2016

Microverse, Remote Full Stack Web Development Program: Apr 2023 – Aug 2023

- Spent 1300+ hours mastering algorithms, data structures, and full-stack development while simultaneously developing projects with JavaScript, React, and Redux.
- Developed skills in remote pairprogramming using GitHub, industrystandard Gitlow, and daily standups to communicate and collaborate with international remote developers.

PROJECTS

Accounting (2023 - Present)

E-commerce Platform (2022 - 2023)

CRM (2022 - 2023)

CERTIFICATES:

- JavaScript Algorithms and Data Structures
- Responsive Web Design

LANGUAGES

English: C1
Persian: Native